{
  "Science": [
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What is the speed of light?",
      "a": "299,792,458 m/s",
      "b": "1,000 m/s",
      "c": "Instant",
      "d": "Light is an illusion",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "How many protons does hydrogen have?",
      "a": "1",
      "b": "2",
      "c": "3",
      "d": "4",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "How did Earth's moon form?",
      "a": "The debris from the Big Bang formed the Earth and the moon at the same time.",
      "b": "A slow meteor got caught in the Earth's gravitational pull.",
      "c": "The moon is also an illusion.",
      "d": "A planet colided with a young Earth and the debris formed the moon.",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What type of feeder is a cat?",
      "a": "Omnivore",
      "b": "Herbivore",
      "c": "Carnivore",
      "d": "Photosynthesizer",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What is the biggest volcano on Earth?",
      "a": "Olympus Mons",
      "b": "Ojos del Salado",
      "c": "PÃ¡same la sal",
      "d": "Mount Fuji",
      "answer": "b"
    }
  ],
  "Technology": [
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What was the first programmable computer?",
      "a": "The ZX Spectrum",
      "b": "The Z1",
      "c": "Macintosh 128K",
      "d": "Atari 2600",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What is the worlds most powerful computer?",
      "a": "Trinity",
      "b": "Summit",
      "c": "Ugaka",
      "d": "Piz Daint",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "Currently, who has made the worlds smallest computer?",
      "a": "University of Michigan",
      "b": "Compaq",
      "c": "IBM",
      "d": "Microsoft",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What is the highest frame per second achieved by a machine?",
      "a": "144hz",
      "b": "244hz",
      "c": "60hz",
      "d": "4.4 trillion hz",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "How far can a laser travel?",
      "a": "200 duodecillion meters",
      "b": "436 quintillion meters",
      "c": "Infinitely",
      "d": "1 whole universe",
      "answer": "c"
    }
  ],
  "Engineering": [
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What is the purpose of a gear?",
      "a": "To make a funny sound that may aggravate some.",
      "b": "To cause smooth friction to transfer energy to each shaft.",
      "c": "To transfer rotary motion via teeth from one shaft to another",
      "d": "To crush items between the teeth.",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "How does a car engine work?",
      "a": "Combustion pushes the pistons in the engine that turns the crank shaft.",
      "b": "Pure road rage runs the engine.",
      "c": "The engine acts as an amplifier for the battery to move the car.",
      "d": "The engine is composed of a battery that moves the pistons.",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "How does aviation work on a plane?",
      "a": "The engines alone propel the plane forward.",
      "b": "The wings vibrate at an unseeable speed and lift the plane.",
      "c": "The wings have a magnetic field that lifts the plane.",
      "d": "The design of the wings causes air pressure to lift the plane.",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "How does an electric rotor work?",
      "a": "The induction of a current flow causes through stator windings cause the rotor to move.",
      "b": "Batteries.",
      "c": "The current causes the electrons in the rotor to shift on the edges in a circular motion.",
      "d": "There are small gears that go in one direction when powered by electricity.",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What was the first facility to produce electricity generated by nuclear energy?",
      "a": "The Springfield Nuclear Power Plant",
      "b": "Vladimir Ilyich Lenin Nuclear Power Plant",
      "c": "Pearl Street Station",
      "d": "The Experimental Breeder Reactor-1",
      "answer": "d"
    }
  ],
  "Math": [
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "Whos known as the \"Father of Algebra\"?",
      "a": "Albert Einstein",
      "b": "Muhammad al-Khwarizmi",
      "c": "Euclid of Alexandria",
      "d": "Pythagoras of Samos",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "what are the order of operations?",
      "a": "Parenthesis , exponent, multiplication, division, addition, subtraction",
      "b": "Division, multiplication, subtraction, addition, parenthesis, exponent",
      "c": "Subtraction, addition, exponent, multiplication, parenthesis, division",
      "d": "Addition, parenthesis, subtraction, exponent, multiplication, division",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What do the degrees of the interiar angles of a Triangle add up to?",
      "a": "90",
      "b": "180",
      "c": "270",
      "d": "360",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What method do we use to multiply two polynomials?",
      "a": "The Vertex Formula",
      "b": "The Quadratic Formula",
      "c": "The FOIL Method",
      "d": "The Pythagorean Theorem",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "type": "text",
      "question": "What is the imaginary number i?",
      "a": "22/7",
      "b": "1",
      "c": "That's a letter and it's very real.",
      "d": "The square root of -1",
      "answer": "d"
    }
  ]
}
